Good morning. It's Friday, March 20th.
It's Ted Rall and John Kiriakou with D
Program with Ted Rall and John Kiriakou.
Good morning, John. Good morning, Ted.
How are you? I'm good, good. Let's talk
about today. Uh you know, I always try
to make the rundown short, but the news
doesn't cooperate. No. Uh
let's go through it. Uh Defense
Department wants $200 billion for for uh
we don't know how much Iran war. Uh
Congress wasn't consulted, so we're
going to find out are they going to pay
up anyway? Um Can I interrupt you on
that? Can I interrupt you?
Congress was not consulted. And what's
funny is now the really hardcore
Republicans are starting to say, "Well,
like the MAGA guys, well, you know, we
don't want to put our our war fighters
in harm's way, so Mhm.
>> going to have to give it to them. We
shouldn't Now's not the time to be
asking questions."
Bunch of cowards.
From what I can gather, John, even
adjusted for inflation, this is more
than the cost of the entire Gulf War.
Yeah, I'm sure that's true. And I mean
so
>> And we don't
>> the Gulf War, we had that thing called
burden sharing, where we actually made
the Kuwaitis pay for everything.
Yeah, pay for the cost of their own
liberation.
Always a always a Well, Bush had that
idea for Iraq, too, but I don't know how
that worked out. Um yeah, I don't we'll
see how So, I I'm curious to see how I
mean, Congress is a bunch of lick
spittles, but we'll see what happens. Um
Iran, okay, so here's what we've got. Uh
they've been squeezing the Strait of
Hormuz. Iran uh Iran attacked Qatar's
Ras Laffan uh natural liquid natural gas
facilities. Um Qatar says Qatar says
that their uh export capacity is down by
17% and that it'll take at least 3 to 5
years to repair. Oil shot up to a is at
$108 a barrel. Uh
>> Down from 115 just a few hours ago. And
who knows where it's going to go next.
Um the this part, John, made me laugh so
much. The US is uh is thinking of
lifting sanctions on Iranian oil at sea.
Uh so in other words, we go to war
against Iran
and then uh after oil Iranian oil has
been sanctioned for years and because we
attacked them
that we're going to have to lift the or
the because the prices are going up so
high.
>> And and there's something to that.
Uh know, Trump has been talking tough
about, you know, we're going to have to
just tighten our belts. We're going to
have to just pay a little bit extra.
We're going to have to be all in this
together. And then
an Indian ship paid for the oil in yuan.
Mhm.
>> And this was yesterday and the Iranians
said, "Okay, free to pass." No, that's
the $2 million
>> "Wait a minute, wait a minute. The oil
has to be paid for in dollars, otherwise
it's going to crash our economy." And
they said, "Tough luck for you." So then
we lifted sanctions on Iranian oil.
And and that said was that the $2
million fee that there's Yeah, one So,
that I Yeah, I read about that. Um and
then Netanyahu says basically Trump is
pressing Netanyahu to say that Israel
acted alone in its attack uh on that gas
facility in Iran. Uh who knows what the
truth is there. Uh I I have my
suspicions. I suspect you do, too. Um
meanwhile, we're forgetting all about
Gaza. Um where Hamas is still in charge.
Um the mediators in Cairo have handed
Hamas a proposal that basically says,
"You should hand over all your weapons
and we're going to have some new Gaza
authority take over." Yes.
>> Uh and the uh we don't know what it's
going to be. Uh but basically Hamas is
now saying, "You know what? We like the
way this Iran war is going and we're
going to we're not getting back to you
until we see how that plays out."
Um and then J.D. Vance, I thought this
was fascinating. He's worried about the
unpopularity of the war and he's
signaling to people close to him that he
may not run for president in 2028. I
think he's a sure loser. I really do.
He's young. He can run 10, 20, 30 years
from now if he wants. True. And still be
plenty young.
Um I think that if he were to run in in
2 years, sure loser. I agree with that.
>> tied to Donald Trump.
I agree with that. Um 65% of Americans
tell the latest Reuters poll that they
think Trump will order a large-scale
ground invasion of Iran just like Iraq.
Uh 7% say they would be okay with it. Uh
broader approval rating for Trump is
hovering around 40%. That's a couple of
points higher than it's been. I
attribute that to the rally around the
flag effect. Uh and John Denmark was
preparing to They were really, really
scared that Trump was going to invade
Greenland. Um they actually had plans to
send troops to Greenland to uh line up
all the airstrips with bombs and blow up
all the airstrips. They had blood
supplies ready to go. Uh they really
thought that there was a there was a
possibility and then they weren't going
to play, either. They weren't going to
take it lying down.
God bless them.
Um
Uh I mean, what can you say? I I every
time I encounter a Dane, I want to
apologize on behalf of the American
government. Fair.
Totally fair.
But Uh you're right. They did all the
things that you just said they did
because they genuinely believed Donald
Trump was going to invade Greenland.
Insane that we got that it got to that
point. Um and and you know who knows?
That that crisis could uh
>> [clears throat]
>> you know, the the Greenland topic keeps
popping up again like a meerkat. Um
the analogy I don't get to use too
often. Um
>> [laughter]
>> So, John, uh we have a bunch of leftover
super chats from yesterday that I
promised we're going to get to first
thing or maybe second thing, but let's
let's kill a story or two first before
we do that. What do you want to talk
about first?
Uh yeah, let's let's talk about the
Gulf. I think we should we should
probably talk about the Gulf since
that's sort of where all eyes are
pointing.
Um
listen, it's it's worse than it was
yesterday. Yeah. This is not
this is not going to end quickly. It's
not going to end easily or nicely. It's
going to be hideous. The United States
announced um yesterday afternoon that it
had killed the IRGC spokesman. Now
killed the head of the IRGC. Killed the
minister who's in charge of the IRGC.
Now we killed the spokesman.
Um
uh Benjamin Netanyahu is not dead. A
couple of
podcasters who until yesterday were
highly respected um said, "The reason we
haven't seen Netanyahu is he's dead. The
reason why we haven't seen his son
is because he was sitting shiva for 7
days. He went quiet on Twitter for
exactly 7 days Mhm. and then retweeted
something yesterday because Netanyahu's
dead. And then Netanyahu gave a press
conference.
Oops.
>> Interesting.
Yeah, so he's not dead.
Yeah. Yeah. There are plenty of bunkers
in in Israel. They're all over Israel.
Everybody has a bunker. I saw I saw a
bunker yesterday. I I was walking back
from the the speaking event with this
young guy and um and he says, "Hey, you
want to see Hitler's bunker? You can't
really go into it right now." And I
said, "Yeah, sure." He's like, "It's
right there across the street. It's a
laser tag place now."
>> [laughter]
>> I know it was used to be under a car
park, right?
>> Uh-huh. It is. It still is. The car park
is under
>> honestly I think they should dig it up
and uh and turn it into a uh tourist
attraction. I would totally go. I think
it would be awesome.
I mean
>> Totally. I would totally be there. I'd
pay whatever the price was. Yeah,
totally. Um
you know, I understand why a lot why
they didn't do it for a long time, but I
mean, I think enough time has passed. Um
So, John, um you know, where are we when
it comes to uh you know, I mean, I think
we may see $150 a barrel oil and you
know
the conventional wisdom here is that
basically the price of gas in the United
States tax uh exactly one for one uh to
the price per per barrel of oil. If
that's true if you're if you're
currently looking at uh gas prices that
are like $3.85 or $4 a gallon like most
parts of the United States um you could
be seeing seven or eight dollars a
gallon. Um you know, cuz we're now at
twice uh pre-war per barrel prices. I
mean will Americans freak out in
California when oil is when gas prices
go to four digits go to $11 a gallon?
>> Yeah. I mean, just at a normal gas
station. I was just in LA 2 weeks ago.
In normal gas station
you're like, "Oh, it's only $5.50 a
gallon. I got to grab that." Right.
Right. know, you go to the airport and
it's like seven a gallon. Right.
>> right. That's that's under a normal
circumstance. This reminds me it reminds
me of the hyperinflation in Turkey where
like I would get up in the morning and
exchange I want to exchange my you know,
my da I my my dollars as late as
possible, just a little bit at a time
because I'd get more lira
later in the day.
Yeah. Um This is
>> Exactly right. I mean you know you and
both have you know, we've lived long
enough to hear you know presidential
campaigns affected by a 10 cent or 20
cent deviation in gas prices. This is a
lot more than that. I mean you know what
about the political ramifications this
fall? I mean does that still matter? Cuz
now the spin we're hearing on social
media from the Republicans are "It's a
small price to pay a little more at the
pump to liberate 92 million Iranians."
Is it? Yeah.
Yeah, that's that's what they're going
to go with. The problem is that the
Iranians don't want our liberation.
They've been clear about it from the
beginning. We overstepped. We
overreached like we always do. And like
we always do, we have no exit strategy.
And then I wanted to reach into the TV
this morning, Ted, and punch Benjamin
Netanyahu in the face when somebody said
something about about
Israel's war with Iran. And he said,
"Oh, no, no, no.
This is America's war. We're America's
ally. The Americans are the heroes
here."
>> [laughter]
>> I was like, "You [__] asshole." He He
just played Donald Trump from beginning
to end. He is an [__] and he's a
smart [__] too, though.
>> Yes, he is smart.
Um that that's that's amazing spin. Um
you you know, how much daylight is there
between Israel and the United States in
this war?
I think only a little bit. And I say
only a little bit because
the Israelis have done a couple things
like like trying to blow up um the uh
South Pars
that the Americans didn't want to do.
You know, we we call it South Pars. Only
Only a third of it is called South Pars.
The southern two thirds are called the
North Dome. And they're in Qatari
waters.
Yeah, they're it's underneath This is
all under the um Persian Gulf. Yeah.
>> Exactly, it's underneath. And so, if
you're going to hit one, the other one
gets hit, too, kind of automatically.
And it just leads to from from one
problem to another problem. And the
Qataris are like, "What are you guys
doing?"
But the Israelis hate Qatar
because the Qataris are pro-Hamas. And
so, they're happy to they're happy to
bomb the gas field and then say, "Oh,
sorry. You know what? We didn't realize
that the Americans didn't want us to
bomb that. Sorry." And then Trump is
like, "They bombed it, but I told them
to stop, and they stopped." No, they
knew exactly what they were doing.
No, they definitely [clears throat] did.
Um Saudi Arabia says they're getting
impatient. Um they're threatening Iran.
They're saying all trust is lost between
them. They just, you know, they had
nascent diplomatic relations that only
go back 3 years, barely. Yeah, barely,
barely. And And so
>> After decades of of no relations. So now
basically they're kind of like, "Yeah,
you have relations, but that's about
it." Um
you know, with the South What would the
South What would a Saudi slap back at
Iran for hitting Saudi facilities and
Saudi targets look like?
You know, this is going to sound silly,
but it's actually quite important. First
of all, the Saudis could um
could
break relations again, or even just
recall ambassadors. I wouldn't be
surprised if they broke relations. But
if you really want to hurt the Iranians,
you forbid Iranians from uh making the
Hajj,
the pilgrimage to Mecca. They did that
for a couple of years, 1979,
1980, 1981.
And it was a crisis, let me tell you. I
bet. crisis to the point where the
Iranians started carrying out terrorist
attacks against Saudis. They supported
the the takeover of the of the Dome of
the Rock by Saudi radicals.
People were killed. It's a bad
situation. My guess is that's what the
Saudis are going to start with. Just ban
all Iranians from the Hajj. So
interesting. So not a military response.
No, the thing is is the
And every time I say this, I take [__]
from Saudis, but I'm going to say it
again cuz it's true. There are very few
Saudis in the Saudi military. They're
almost all Pakistanis.
The The leadership are Saudis. The
generals, the colonels, they're all
Saudis.
But the lower-level officers and all the
grunts,
they're all Pakistanis.
So they don't really care one way or the
other. They just do as they're told.
You know, John, I just got to say before
we move on to the Hamas thing and to
start and start dealing with the
questions. And by the way, please like,
follow, and share the show. Please go
ahead and put your questions into the
live chat if you're watching live at
9:00 a.m. Eastern time. Um and uh that
both in Rumble and YouTube, and we
really appreciate you. Um super chats
get priority, unfortunately. That's just
how it is. Um so let's see. Um
You What do you think the um
the you I mean
I keep I have to just say every morning
I wake up and I'm worried that something
really big, like the Turkmenistan thing
that we talked about yesterday, is going
to happen. We're something big is going
to blow up, and not in We're going to
have a massive ecological and
environmental disaster to deal with on a
global scale, and no ability or will to
deal with it. I mean, you know, putting
out oil fires is extremely difficult and
complicated.
>> Yeah, and it's it's not like, you know,
the Exxon Valdez, where you just, you
know, everybody just runs there and
starts taking Dawn dish soap and
cleaning off animals. This is an active
war zone.
Right.
>> get there.
Right. And you would need incredible
amounts of you know, brilliant engineers
and so and you know, amazing huge
amounts of demolitions
well placed to cave in the hole so that
you start you you have a chance of
putting out an oil or a gas fire. But
it's not it's it's no it's not piece
it's no piece of cake cake. We've The
one in Turkmenistan that we talked
about, it's been going since 1971.
>> And you know what? We didn't talk about
Centralia, Pennsylvania yesterday. Oh,
right. Centralia, Pennsylvania is is a
it's a ghost town now in the middle of
Pennsylvania. In the 1950s the whole
town sits on top of a a seam of coal,
right? Bituminous coal.
And um in the 1950s
somehow the coal caught on fire.
Somebody dropped a cigarette or knocked
over a lantern or whatever, but in the
'50s it caught fire.
>> Even static electricity could do it.
Even static electricity. It is still
burning. Mhm.
And if you've ever you can still drive
through Centralia. The whole place is
abandoned. Nobody lives there anymore.
But everywhere you look, there's just
smoke coming out of these holes in the
ground.
And it's going to burn for the next 500
years. It's insane. Is there no
political will to to fix it?
>> No political will at all. They talked
about how they would do it. You know,
you could put Like they put out the
Kuwaiti oil fires, you put Rolls-Royce
jet engines above the holes and then
blow them out. Oh, wow. Um but even that
they the the seam is so big. It could go
for miles. It could go for hundreds of
miles. We don't know.
Yeah, a lot of that part of the
Yeah, the Ohio, Kentucky, and and and
Pennsylvania have a lot of caves. It's
kind of like Oh my god.
Oh, we used to we used to do that on
weekends, just go caving, spelunking.
Yeah.
>> Walk through caves. Yeah.
Good time. For sure. Definitely for
awesome for kids. Um what Hamas, let's
talk about that. I mean, uh you know,
Hamas uh
they're sitting pretty. Two and a half,
you know,
it's been 2 and 1/2 years since October
7th, 2023.
Um you know, the Israelis flattened
Gaza, but they didn't flatten Hamas.
They're still the only game in town. And
it's And seems like they've been really
They feel like their take is
uh Israel is tied is bogged down in
Lebanon and in uh Iran. They don't have
time to deal with us. They you know,
they they're not going to be able to
deal with us. We're still here like
cockroaches. You can't kill us. Um and
they but they're being told nevertheless
as part of the ceasefire deal, uh
"Hand over all of your weapons." And
they're like,
"Yeah, we're we're not going to do that
not anytime soon." I mean, what's going
to happen is there's a deadline, right,
approaching for these negotiations. I
mean, can Israel like I mean, I suppose
they could go back to genociding.
I mean, it's not exactly a target-rich
environment anymore in Gaza. No, there's
nothing left to blow up. They've blown
it all up.
So what do you what do you think's going
to happen there?
Um
I think that, as crazy as it might
sound, Hamas is actually in the catbird
seat right now. Hilarious.
>> [laughter]
>> The Israelis
the Israelis can't force them to take
this deal because they're preoccupied in
both Iran and Lebanon.
Hezbollah's putting up a
a tougher fight than the Israelis had
expected. Mhm. Not to say that
Hezbollah's winning, they're not.
They're getting [snorts] creamed. But
they're fighting back. There are almost
1 million Lebanese on the run right now,
internally displaced, with nowhere to go
because they're surrounded by by Syria
on two sides, Israel on one, and the
Mediterranean Sea on the fourth.
So there's nowhere to go.
So
You know, for [clears throat] me, the
big the big takeaway of all of this, the
big meta headline is
air wars are overrated.
You can say that again.
Um all right, so we do
>> you for one second, real quick.
We all sent around footage yesterday of
an F-35 being hit by Iranian ground
fire.
Uh at first, people were saying, "No,
it's AI.
It's [__] It's a stealth fighter.
They're invisible." No, the Iranians hit
it. And not only did they hit it, they
wounded the pilot to the point where
this morning, the Pentagon released a
state a statement saying that he made it
back to an airbase in the Middle East
and that he's in stable condition. So
he's admitted to the hospital.
He's been wounded.
But nobody is saying
why, how the Iranians,
whom, to use the president's word, we
have obliterated, he said it twice
yesterday,
how they were able to hit an invisible
plane
that is the
art
of the American force. True.
Another question is why didn't why
didn't the pilot eject? Yeah.
Well, probably
because he didn't want the Iranians to
get the plane. They would turn it over
immediately to the Russians and the
Chinese and then we're screwed.
Yeah, well and I you know my my my
father, you know, was in the Air Force
and he project manager for a lot of
these fighter projects and he said
fighter one of the problems is that they
fighter fighter pilots really don't want
to eject. Like they want to they're
they're so trained to try to fix every
problem to the last second that
sometimes they wait past the last
second.
And
they're just so they're so like in love
with their their machine, you know, they
just don't want to let it go. It's like
captain of the ship. Um
let's do some questions from yesterday.
Uh
Hawk Hawko, thanks for the $7.99
Australian dollars. Trump points the
finger at Israel for the attack on South
Pars. A sign of the relationship
fracturing? Is Trump trying to back off
by shifting focus?
Um I I don't think the relationship is
fracturing. I think there are always
disagreements in times of war and I
think Trump is probably getting a little
sick and tired of Netanyahu pushing all
the blame onto him.
I think that's what it is. Yeah, I think
that's my take too. Um so here's a super
chat from March 18th when John you were
out. Hey John, I'm a 21 and by the way
thanks for the $19.99. Uh hey John, I'm
a 21-year-old student pursuing a career
in intelligence analysis.
What degrees of study would be the most
applicable to the modern day in your
opinion? What information and media
should I be consuming? Sorry, it's so
small to familiarize myself with the
world of analysis. Thank you.
That's a great question.
Um
I would focus [snorts] on your
geographical
um area of interest. For me it was the
Middle East. Some people devoted their
whole lives to Latin America,
Eurasia, China, whatever.
Um become the go-to person on that issue
and honestly consume everything,
everything.
I don't mean, you know, go to InfoWars
and watch people blow VA for 2 hours
every day.
But
but in your field, in your area, be sure
to get everything.
I I would even force myself through,
you know, Foreign Affairs magazine which
is sometimes so dense and the article's
usually written by people who have never
actually created or implemented foreign
policy, they've just studied it. But you
have to know what everybody is saying.
And you know, oftentimes
and I mean this literally, oftentimes
there are issues that I know I'm going
to have to comment on that I just simply
haven't formed an opinion on.
And so I need to see what other people
whom I respect
are saying
so that I can form my own opinion.
Yeah, about foreign policy, I feel like
that's like why I used to like to read
Time and Newsweek just to know what
mainstream middle America was being
spoon-fed. Foreign policy is like what
the Beltway is thinking. Exactly right.
Exactly right.
>> like a month or so ago Foreign Policy
basically started admitting that Ukraine
had lost the war.
And that's like well that's sort of, you
know, you and I were talking about that
years ago.
But like it you know, basically it's
like okay, so that means the
establishment has accepted it.
Um
Pink Lady Apples 83, thanks for the $5.
Hey Studs, John are you going to do a
book signing tour with your new book
coming out? If so, could you please come
to Atlanta or North Georgia? I need a
selfie with those gorgeous dimples. You
guys are the best. I get it narcissist.
Thank you.
>> [laughter]
>> I got to tell you
um Tony Lyons from Skyhorse Publishing
called me the other day and he said and
Tony's the owner the the publisher.
And he said uh
he said you're you're everywhere in my
feed, you're on you're on Instagram,
you're on TikTok, you're on YouTube and
I said I know I I I can't figure it out,
you know, this kid cut my videos up and
you know,
I I told him the same story I tell
everybody else.
So he said we decided to republish your
your three books um the CIA Insiders
Guides to Surveillance and Surveillance
Detection, Lying and Lie Detection,
Disappearing and Living off the Grid,
but we're going to do them in one fat
book. Can can you update them?
And I was like, yeah, I guess so. When
do you want them by? He's like,
Saturday? I said Tony
>> [laughter]
>> 550 pages, I can't do it by Saturday.
>> his mind? So he said he said uh Tucker
Carlson's going to write the
introduction. I said, oh nice, I'll call
him and thank him. Mhm.
He sent it the next day.
Wow. So I call him, I was like, you
wrote the introduction in 1 day? He's
like, well, it's not that long. I Yeah,
he said I just dashed it off. But you
need to get this book out. I said we we
actually don't, it's all still in print.
They just want to want to repackage it
and and update it. So I'm going to do
that.
They want me to update the CIA Insiders
Guide to the Iran Crisis which is going
to be a bigger work since we're at war.
Um I've got the Cemetery book
that was supposed to be out actually in
in 4 days and um
and now is postponed 2 months for
reasons that are inexplicable to me.
And I've got the Mafia book that is done
and I'm just waiting on a release date
and now I'm writing a book of stories. I
I got to get all my stories all in one
place
and release that. So it's going to be a
big
a big book year. But yeah, uh you know,
now that I now that I have a really
great literary agent, um
I'm hoping that
my books from now on will be published
just by one of the big five
and my best relationship is with Simon
and Schuster since they've done several
of my other books. And so Simon and
Schuster, Random House, Penguin, Knopf,
all those guys, um Putnam,
they uh they have
PR budgets.
And so they will send me on a book tour.
It won't be extensive, but I'm going to
I'm going to do my best. Yeah, book
tours are good. Yeah. Decatur, Georgia
has a great book festival. Really?
Yeah. Uh LA does too. Yeah, that's true.
John, I've been reading Director
Director at S by Steve Coll. From your
experience, where does it get the CIA,
Pakistan and the and Afghanistan war
right? And where does it miss nuance? Um
thanks for the and thanks for the $5,
Ryan. I thank you, Ryan. I I hate
complimenting Steve Coll.
Uh
Steve Coll wrote an article about me in
the New Yorker called The Spy Who Talked
Too Much.
And I wanted to punch him in his face.
And that was after I welcomed him into
my home and he like held my kids.
What what did the article say? You know,
Barrett, you know they don't always
write
the the author doesn't write the
headline. Yeah, and he said that to me
when I called him to yell at him from
prison no less. That's true though. Uh I
know it's true. Yeah, I never ever write
my own headlines, never.
Yeah, I I always suggest I always
suggest one, they almost never use it.
Twice I've I've suggested headlines that
people have used, both times at
Consortium News. Mhm. But Steve Coll is
actually one of the country's great
writers, one of the country's great
investigative journalists and he's in
addition to being an investigative
journalist, he's the dean of the School
of Journalism at Columbia. Mhm. So he's
a very big deal. That book was
excellent, I have to say. And I'm not
sure he missed nuance. I think he pretty
well got it. Mhm.
I read one of his other books and and I
did like it. Um Yeah, I wanted I as I
read it I wanted to criticize him and I
couldn't.
He didn't write the headline, John.
>> [laughter]
>> $4.99, thank you so much. I work at the
EPA and I'm wondering what you think
think about the EPA rescinding the
greenhouse gas endangerment finding.
Thank you. #pardonjohn.
Uh thank you.
Yeah, I I I lose sleep over these over
these issues. I really do.
Um and the only solace that I take is
something that I told a friend this
morning.
There's only 2 and 1/2 more years of
this.
Like even if a Republican
wins,
it likely won't be as bad. Like with the
wholesale deregulation across the board
deregulation and you know, putting up
statues of slave owners in Washington
D.C. which they announced yesterday they
were doing and
you know, it's
>> Trying to make it so married women can't
vote. Yeah, um charging people with
murder for taking an abortion pill which
also happened yesterday, changing the
name of the Kennedy Center to the Trump
Kennedy Center, minting a gold coin with
his face on both sides. Mhm. Yeah, this
is
>> Bashi. Yeah, it's Turkmenistan Bashi all
over again.
>> [clears throat]
>> Um
I mean John, the thing is though, even
if we were to get President AOC,
uh which I don't think we're going to
get, uh but if we were, you know, you
and I both know Democrats wouldn't roll
back most of this stuff.
>> they wouldn't because they're because
they're cowards.
Yeah. And because they want the power
and authority for themselves. Yeah.
I mean, that's the thing is like uh you
know,
Joe Biden did not roll back much of the
Trump first term stuff at all.
>> No, in fact Joe Biden never
reestablished relations with Cuba which
had been the crown jewel of the Trump
Biden foreign policy.
Uh Steve and uh thanks for the uh two
Canadian dollars. Ted, are you in a
bathroom?
No, I respect my viewers too much to be
in a bathroom to do while doing a show.
If you say I think you are.
I could say no, I understand the
question.
>> [laughter]
>> Thanks for the dollar. Shout out to
Cutter for the worst return on a $400
million bribe, the airplane to Trump. I
I forgot about that in modern history.
That's true. Have have you so your your
your dollar is well placed. Royce bet
1999. Hey John and Ted, I'm a US
Filipino citizen. My question is how is
the war in Iran going to affect the US
Philippines alliance? The Filipino
people are suffering from the effects of
this war.
I'm wondering how the Filipino Do you
know? I
how why Filipinos would be suffering?
>> US Philippine relations are are very
close right now. I think the Philippines
The Philippines imports all of its oil.
Mhm. And um
Yeah. And and and people are poor there.
Yeah. And this is just going to just
push people into misery.
And it's all going
They have a lot of light manufacturing
like uh cheap clothing and stuff like
that. That's also going to be affected
by this.
Um Yeah.
I don't know. I mean
>> can't believe I can't imagine that the
conversation yesterday between Trump and
the and the new Japanese Prime Minister
was terribly warm. Not just because he
mentioned Pearl Harbor.
Like because Japan imports literally
100% of its oil. Mhm.
>> They have zero oil or natural gas.
>> Which is how Pearl Harbor start happened
in the first place because we had a US
naval blockade of oil
imports to Japan. That's right. And the
Japanese were desperate and they were
basically trying to bloody our nose and
telling tell us to [__] off and leave
them alone.
>> It's true. Um
Bryson, thanks for the uh 999. Um third
super chat this week.
Thank you for the love the show. Thank
you for your support. How would you both
rank Bush, Obama, Trump, and Biden?
That's a good question. And if you had
to live under one of those presidents
for the rest of your life, God forbid,
uh which would you choose?
>> Oh my God, what a question.
It's a great question. Well, Biden was
having no president at all, basically.
I would say. Yeah.
>> Um Everything was on autopilot. Yeah, I
mean so that's pretty rough. I mean, I
guess you could say it's a tribute to
the American system that you could that
it survived that. Yeah. Um
I feel like Trump one and Trump two are
two totally different animals. So those
almost have to be separated.
Um
Uh I hated George W. Bush. I hated
Barack Obama.
I'm going to have to say I'd go with
Barack Obama because um he presented the
least bad outward-looking face to the
world, even though he was busily droning
people in places like Pakistan and you
know,
pissing people off all over the place
that we didn't know about. But still
Bush I thought was reckless. Um
So I guess I'd go with Obama, even
though I really I can't stand them.
>> [snorts]
>> Um
You know what? In good conscience, I
just can't with Obama. Because of what
he did to you personally. He He
prosecuted me and not just me, but seven
other whistleblowers. Yeah.
>> He He's
the the
the worst, harshest enemy of
whistleblowers in American history.
And the worst part is that was burnt
that was peak brunch Democrats, too. You
know, everybody went home and put their
protest signs in the in the closet
because Obama was president. Yeah.
And Robbie's pointing out in our chat
that it was Obama who destroyed Libya. I
would add it was Obama who destroyed
Syria and Somalia, too. One part
Somalia. And Honduras. And and Honduras,
that's right. Thank you, Hillary
Clinton. Yep. Um and he appointed not
just Hillary Clinton as Secretary of
State, but Hillary Clinton and John
Kerry.
So no, thank you. Um
Bush was a war criminal.
So that's a hard no. Yeah.
Trump, I mean, what are you going to
say? Biden, you're right, the country
was running itself. For me personally,
the least damaging of all those
presidents was Joe Biden.
That's true. Least damaging.
You know, I mean
>> what a choice, huh? It's like you want
to punch a
>> was pretty good in Trump under Trump
one. Mhm. Pretty good. Uh but then the
way he behaved recklessly with COVID
bizarre, you know? I mean, on the other
hand, I I give him credit because I
don't think
I don't think President Hillary Clinton
would have approved the vaccine.
Um you know, to go so quickly.
You don't think so? I do. I think
Democrats are they would be so obsessed
with the testing process. Be like, uh
let's take 5 years and
Do you remember those idiots some
married couple in uh
Arizona? Trump mens mentioned something
about I forget what and it happened to
be
an ingredient in their pool chemicals.
And so they they ate the pool chemicals
and they both died.
Yes, I do [laughter] remember that.
Dar The Darwin Award goes to Yeah.
Uh
Vilmer 80 Whatever happened to the
Darwin Award? Do they still do that? It
was used to be one of my favorite
things. Yeah. I used to love that thing.
Uh Vilmer Air 8791, thanks for the two
Canadian dollar. What are the odds that
Trump brings up Hitler to the German
Chancellor? Not zero.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah.
Not zero. It should be zero. Um Shawn
thanks for the 499. And to think Cutter
don't Okay, donated that expensive plane
only to get bombed by Israel and Iran
within a year. Great minds think alike.
Uh
Bailey, thanks for the 499 pounds. I'm
interested in your opinions on Piers
Morgan, especially regarding his false
publication of US troops torturing Iraqi
prisoners.
You know, I have to say that I've kind
of come around on Piers Morgan. I
loathed
Piers Morgan. I really did. And then his
producers started hounding me to go on
the show. Mhm. And and I went and he
treated me really well. And then
a couple of times ago that I went on
I was on with Scott Horton and I have
the deepest respect for Scott Horton.
Uh libertarian Scott Horton, not the
Atlantic Monthly journalist Scott
Horton. Although he's okay, too.
But um I was on with libertarian Scott
Horton, Alan freaking Dershowitz and uh
General Danny Ayalon from the Mossad.
And in the end What What a group. Oh, it
was it was harsh, man. And they were at
each other's throats. And I was just
kind of sitting there watching the whole
thing play out. And then finally Piers
says to me um John, we haven't really
heard from you, he says
um do you consider Hamas to be
uh a a terrorist organization? And I
said I didn't until October 7th when
they attacked civilians. Mhm. Fair. I I
believed that they were
a a liberation organization. But when
they when they murdered civilians, yes.
Agreed. He says, do you believe October
7th was a terrorist attack? I said, in
part, yes. Mhm. Um well, what then
what's your position on Gaza? I said,
the Israelis are wrong and they need to
get out of Gaza immediately. I said,
listen, Piers, the bottom line is this,
you can't have as your policy kill
everybody. That's the definition of
genocide. And if anybody should know
genocide, it should be the Israelis.
Mhm. And then he said
and I I was very heartened by this. He
said um I've finally come around on this
issue and I have to agree with you.
And he's been Joe Zionist from the very
beginning.
>> Yeah. I've seen that I've seen that
transformation with Piers, also.
Um you know, I mean, again
um you know, one would hope that you'd
have the moral clarity to see something
like that on you know, October 8th,
2023, but better late than never,
seriously. Yeah. Yeah. Trump thanks for
uh sorry, Yass Yass thanks for the uh
1799 Emirati dirham. Uh Trump rarely
makes an unwitting political mistake. If
you had to guess
I wouldn't say that's true. If you
What's a mad genius strategy we might
not see? But I'm just going to push back
on that. Uh the Save America Act is a
and is a is a mistake and the
and the
his opposition to vote to mail-in
ballots during the pandemic uh was a
huge contributing factor to his defeat
to his defeat. Uh so he makes mistakes.
But okay, genius strategy that we might
not see.
Uh let's take that question at its at
its face value. You know, I believe
that he believed
Netanyahu's propaganda that if we
decapitate the Iranian government, the
whole thing comes down like a house of
cards. And I think that he believed that
was the genius strategy.
And instead, he's gotten us into a war
that we're not getting out of. It
Remember,
to win, we need to wipe out the entire
Iranian government and military, which
is not possible.
And install a pro-American
or pro-American and pro-Israeli
government. Essentially a puppet
government. It's not going to happen.
And anything short of that is an
American-Israeli loss.
What what the Iranians need to win is
just to survive
the war.
And they're going to survive. John, one
more question, we'll bring in Robbie. Um
he has some stuff to talk about. Um
What would you say
um
I mean, to my theory that he's kind of
Trump is kind of lost his superpower. He
spent much of his first term still doing
rallies, which was weird, you know,
campaigning. A president continued to
campaign.
But, he kept his ear to the ground,
maybe not with America, but certainly
with half of America, with the
conservative half. Um, and now he
doesn't do that anymore. No more
rallies.
I feel like he's out of touch now. He's
firmly wrapped in DC in Beltway bubble
wrap.
Yeah. And I think that's [__] him
over.
I think that's right.
Yes.
Um,
Okay, one more. Sodan, thanks for the
$19.99. Good morning John, if you were
to have dinner with John Brennan at
Filomena in DC, what would you get off
your chest? Same for Ted, lunch with
your LA Times boss.
What would you ask and would it end with
a handshake? #closure. Great questions.
John, you go first.
Uh, somebody asked me yesterday,
um,
we were we were talking we were talking
about somebody that we mutually hate.
And I said, I can
literally count on one hand the number
of people in my life whom I hate. Mhm.
And I said,
I hate John Brennan. Mhm.
I wouldn't have that meal.
>> up here yesterday on the show, yeah.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, he did. I I wouldn't have that
meal with Brennan. I wouldn't shake his
hand. Mhm.
And frankly,
I I'll say this and I I won't say
anymore. I am working very hard
right now
to see that he spends much of the rest
of his life in prison.
If you could say something to him, what
would you say?
Shame on you.
Monster. Ruiner of families and lives.
Um, the thing I would say, I have no
idea if we would end up with a handshake
or not. I
I wouldn't know until I went into it. I
certainly would sit down with Austin
Butner. Um, but I would ask him,
did you give any thought whatsoever
to the damage you were doing to me
personally as a human being and to this
institution, the the the biggest
newspaper in the state of California.
That's like, did you did you give that
any thought at all?
When Yeah, I I would want to know that.
Um, all right, so let's with that, let's
bring in Robbie West. Robbie, thanks for
coming on and filling us in on what you
have to fill us in on. Yeah, no, of
course. Uh, this will be really quick.
Uh, y'all over on Rumble, uh, John's
newest premium episode is up. Talk about
how he became a internet superstar.
Uh, it is a Rumble exclusive. So, what
y'all need to do, if y'all over on
YouTube, come on over to Rumble. I
promise you the weather is fine. Uh, the
water's the water's okay. It's not
frigid like it is here in Montana.
And uh, y'all can see all of their
premium content here on Rumble. You can
become a Rumble subscriber for $10 a
month or if you just want to support
Dprogram and then just support John and
Ted, you go down on live stream for just
$5 a month and they keep 100% of those
proceeds. Rumble does not take a dime if
you become a channel member, which is
huge. And uh, also Rumble pays them
based off their watch hours as opposed
to ads. So, you're
uh,
they actually earn more money for you
watching here on Rumble just cuz it's
just the way that the just the business
models work. And uh, lastly, uh,
John, for uh,
for you,
uh, more of his content will be going up
on his official Rumble channel today
including shorts. Uh, his channel's
really taking off. It's exploding. So,
thank you everyone that's supporting
that's supporting him.
And also John, do not feel bad about
hating John Brennan. Uh, one of the
things that people have a big
misconception about is that they think
that
Christians are commanded not to hate.
We're not commanded not to hate. We are
commanded to hate and we are commanded
not to hate our brothers
and and to pray for our enemies, but we
are allowed to hate enemies of God. And
John Brennan is 100% that. So, hate
away.
Thank you. And I have a Rumble page,
too, but
>> Yep, he does. Yep, uh,
uh, Ted Rall. So, come on over for more
content on his channel now, too.
Thank you, Robbie. Uh, but do we have an
ad? Uh, we do. I'll throw it up for you.
Thank you.
All right. Well, in the meantime, while
Robbie's doing that, we'll take another
question. Uh, thanks for the dollar from
Desert Fox. Breaking news within the
past 4 hours, Ansar Allah has announced
that they are getting involved and will
join uh,
start joint operations with Iran.
Joint operations are going to be hard
since Ansar Allah is in northern Yemen
and Iran is in Iran and
never the two shall meet. Mhm.
But, good luck. Coordinated?
Maybe. If that means attacking, you
know, shipping in the
in the Red Sea. Yeah. Okay.
>> 90% chance, I would say. Yeah, we're
we've been down that road before and
they're going to get the daylights
bombed out of them. Yeah, yes, they
will. Rainman777,
thanks so much for the $9.99. Do you
think that the American empire is over?
I don't see any way that we can continue
to afford this. Is the economy
permanently cooked? Um, the empire's on
the ropes, I would say.
>> Yeah. Over? No, certainly not.
I agree.
Uh, Kevin Mills, thanks for the $30.
Your favorite retired Oregon sheriff
here. No question, just wanted to say
hi.
>> Hey, yes.
Yes, welcome. Thank you. Go Oregon.
Mhm. That's right. Say I'm represented
by counsel and I don't
>> don't talk to cops.
I like it. Uh, Toast to God, $9.99. I
saw Nuremberg the other day and thought
how boy, have the tables have turned.
Israel is currently moving like Nazis
and it's extremely weird. You can call
them an anti-Semite for pointing it out.
You know, for years every I
I hesitated to say what I'm about to say
and uh, now I'm really convinced that
the Israelis really were
they're
they really were inspired by Nazi
Germany in terms of their tactics. Uh,
you know, the the the the retaliation
against family members, against people
who resist them, uh, the humiliation,
all that stuff is very, very similar.
Oh, we got to go do this ad.
>> lose the ad. All right, we'll do do
that. Sorry about that. Today's sponsor
Chicago Steak Company and they're giving
away four free steaks on every order.
Code BPSIR
free.
Do you ever buy steaks at the grocery
store?
I mean, it's a total gamble. You're
standing there staring staring at
shrink-wrapped mystery cuts trying to
figure out which one might actually be
decent and half the time you get home,
cook it and it's just fine, nothing
special. Chicago Steak Company is the
opposite of that. USDA Prime and upper
choice, hand-selected by butchers in
Chicago, wet-aged 28 to 40 days,
vacuum-sealed and shipped on dry ice
right to your door. Every cut is
hand-carved, no guessing. Here's the
part I really like. Spend $1.99 or more,
any steaks your choice, use code BPSIR
free and they throw in four bourbon
peppercorn sirloins for free plus free
shipping. These are 6-oz top sirloins
with a cracked peppercorn and bourbon
rub. Lean, beefy, bold flavor. Throw
them on a hot grill and they're done in
minutes. That's $160 in free steaks.
15,000 five-star reviews, these guys are
the real deal.
Mychicagosteak.com/rumble.
Code BPSIR free. That's BPSIR free. Link
in the description.
All right. Cool.
So,
uh, yeah, thank you for that, John.
Um,
bop bop bop bop bop. Oh, yeah,
Nuremberg. Uh, so, do you want to
address the Nuremberg thing?
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, I I have to agree with you. I
think that the Israelis learned a lesson
and um, and history is repeating itself.
You know, one of Tucker's
uh, producers reached out to me today
and asked me to retweet um, a statement
from
uh, uh,
Zionist activist saying, I've known
Tucker for 20 years.
The allegation that he's anti-Semitic is
absurd. And then it goes on. I gladly,
happily retweeted it. But, this is where
we are. Now, if you don't follow
Benjamin Netanyahu's
policies down the line,
you're anti-Semitic and that's that's a
damaging accusation.
Very.
>> I how do you convince somebody that no,
I don't I don't hate Jews.
And then the allegation
is, well, maybe secretly you do. So,
maybe you are anti-Semitic. You know,
no.
That double-edged
>> I hate human rights violations
and I hate Benjamin Netanyahu. That
double-edged sword, John, is really I
think now, finally, after all these
years, it's coming back against, you
know, the the Zionist lobby because it
really is causing real anti-Semitism.
Um, you know, it's coming back and so
the two things It is. and it's it's it's
a real problem and they're causing it.
Um,
James Kelly, thanks for the five. Do you
think Israel's going going what they
want at the end of all this?
Well, what they want is to to to disrupt
Iran.
They did disrupt Iran,
but are they going to be in a more
secure position? I don't think so.
No, I don't think so.
I don't think so. Uh like I said, this
policy of just kill everybody, it's
unsustainable.
And you just turn more and more and more
people against you. Now, a clear
majority of Democrats are siding with
Palestinians. A clear majority of
independents are siding with with
Palestinians. They're the Israelis are
doing this to themselves.
The young people are never coming back,
too. That's the thing. It's just with
the passing of time, as you know, the
the people who support Israel, they're
dying of old age. The people who are
coming up, they don't support Israel. I
mean, time is not on Israel on the
Israel on the on the Israeli lobby's
side. That's right.
Just some dude 999, thank you so much.
What do you think is the Did the
definitive breaking point for China's
strategic patience? At what stage does
their limited strategic partnership
transition transition into overt combat?
It's a good question.
I I think it's a good question. We're
not We're not We're not near there. No,
we're not, but we could get there one of
these days.
Yeah. Well, absolutely. Uh David Young,
thanks for the $10. With the midterm
elections coming up, it should be a
no-brainer for Democrats to vote against
the $200 supplement.
>> metal. Shouldn't it? Except for
Fetterman, who has no brains.
Yeah. True. [clears throat]
It should be a no-brainer. It really
should be. It should be. I mean, it
should actually be a no-brainer for
Republicans, too, like uh
Rand Paul. Yes.
Um Pac-Man, 10 bucks, thanks so much. Do
you think there's a possibility or
situation where Saudi Prince MBS is
assassinated,
given the geopolitical ramifications
thereafter? Um John, I'm I'm coming up
empty trying to think of any kind of any
time that there were assassinations
within the Saudi regime.
Once.
>> Who was it? King Faisal was assassinated
by a deranged nephew. Mhm. Um and the
nephew was immediately caught and
immediately executed.
So, there's
>> But he had a long history of mental
illness. So, you're not going to get a
situation like in Where was it? In Was
it Nepal or Bhutan?
>> Nepal. Nepal. Mhm. When Yeah, a nephew
or the crown prince or whoever it was
just wiped out literally. He wiped out
the entire royal family. Crazy. And I
guess some of the guards must have been
in on it or just ran away or whatever.
Um I don't know. Do you see that? I
mean, I I I mean, the MBS's security
must be top-notch.
Yeah, he he rarely appear appears in
public, like actually out in public.
He's very, very difficult to get to. And
of of any Saudi leader
uh in in the history of the country,
he's got the best security.
So, he's probably okay. Rinch Shen,
thanks for the 799 Australian dollars.
Is it Is all diesel and petrol being
price gouged locally to you guys? Yes.
Here in Australia, they might
investigate price gouging in fuel
companies. Yeah, it's total [__]
John, right? I mean, like the gas that's
currently at the pump was was pumped and
refined years ago. Yeah.
Right? That's right.
That's right. Hazel50, thanks for the
fiver, much appreciated. Um DJ Dog 2000,
thanks for the $5. Howdy, John and Ted.
Wondering if you both think Congress
will reclaim any authority.
God, I wonder that, too. Do you see Do
you see the executive getting only more
powerful in the coming years? What does
that mean for the future?
I keep thinking at some [clears throat]
point, but it
there's no sign of it.
That the
that the legislative
>> That's
No, and it and the Democrats in the same
way, just as soon as a Democrat wins the
White House, the Democrats are going to
gladly concede whatever authority they
have on Capitol Hill. 100%. I mean, I
wouldn't be surprised if the SAFE Act
were to pass. Yeah.
Exactly. Uh episode dollar, thanks. The
vaccine was a money grab scam. Um
Kitty Catastrophe, $1.99. John, did you
say Remains of the Day is postponed?
Yeah, um I talked to the publisher about
it last weekend,
and he said that this is not on them,
it's on Amazon.
That Amazon was just slow in the uptake
to to order from the warehouse. So,
instead of March 24th, it's like June
25th, I think.
Mhm.
Yeah. Makes me very angry. Claudio,
thanks for the 5,000 Argentine whatever.
So, I keep saying that. I'm going to
have to look that up. 10 scooter 10
scooters, gasoline shortages and
rationing are daily problem in Southeast
Asia and the Philippines right now. Gas
is beginning Diesel expected for the
next month directly hits tourist
services, so people who who live off it,
the poor is always the are always the
first to suffer. John, you know, with
the day that you were out and Robbie and
I were talking about um we were talking
about how there's countries like uh
Myanmar and Vietnam uh and Singapore
that only have 30 days of gas left uh
before they're
They they run completely dry. Uh Taiwan,
I think is at is has 100 days. Um
there's I mean, that's going to roll
around That's going to come around
sooner rather than later. Um the the
squeeze is really It's hard to
overestimate how harsh this is. Oh,
yeah. Yeah, this is bad. It's like, you
know, American Most Americans are like
one medical disaster away from
bankruptcy. It's the same thing with
whole countries in this case. Mhm. These
countries, as you said, like Singapore,
Myanmar Myanmar is a little bit more
resourceful, I think, but Singapore,
Japan,
they
the economies will just screech to a
halt.
Yeah.
>> And there's only so much oil available
on the on the open market. And if it's
not coming through the Strait of Hormuz,
which accounts for at least 30% of the
world's oil supply,
then they're SOL. And then what do they
do? I I imagine the mullahs down in
their bunker playing a 45 of the Rolling
Stones
Yeah.
>> is on my side, just over on loop.
They just have to They just have to hang
tight. Because time is on their side.
I mean, we we know how to blow [__] up,
but that doesn't mean we know how to
win.
That's right.
Soma, thanks for the
dirhams.
Great thumbnail. Why do you think Iran
has been targeting Gulf countries so
much more than Israel, aside from the
fact that we're much closer?
Well, I think probably
they don't have Iron Dome, right? Also.
No, they don't have Iron Dome.
So, you know, if you only have a certain
number of of missiles, you want to make
them count.
Um and aren't Aren't the Gulf states I
mean, Iran must view the Gulf states as
traitors to the Oh, yeah.
Gulf states and Iran have have always
hated each other. And there was this
uneasy, you know,
coexistence.
But if if the Gulf states are going to
are going to sponsor and house American,
you know, troops and airmen and and
ships and all
all that stuff,
then the Iranians are all in. And the
Abraham By the way, and the Abraham
Accords must have driven them absolutely
crazy.
>> that was That's what added insult to
injury. Yes.
Um so, let's talk about JD Vance.
Um
I know we we mentioned it at the top of
the show, but do you think it Do you
think that it's really true that like
this war would be so unpopular that it
would he wouldn't be able to rinse off
the stink of it in 2028? I don't think
he has time to.
And he's going to have to either break
with Donald Trump now or break with
Donald Trump in 2 years. And I don't
think he can survive that within the
Republican Party. I think it would be
far more advantageous for him if he were
to finish out the term,
go back to Wall Street, make millions
and millions of dollars, and just wait a
little bit like Richard Nixon did. I
mean, I always had this fantasy that
Colin Powell walks up to the UN lectern
says, "They gave me this speech, but
it's all lies."
The music starts to come up. Yeah. Both
parties nominate him in 2004 for
president, right? He runs unopposed. Um
I think something like that might have
happened, right? But I think if JD Vance
were to like resign as vice president
and said, "In good principle in good
faith, I can't support this war. It's
wrong."
But JD Vance That doesn't mean he begets
to become president, right? Because he's
just not beloved. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
Yes, that's it. Even though we might
agree with him and be like, "Good for
you, JD."
Yes. Um
What does it say? And we're going to We
have 30 30 seconds, 45 seconds left.
What does it say that the Danes
were so [__] worried that they were
they shipped explosives to airstrips in
Greenland to protect themselves their
territory from a US invasion?
They believed
they took Donald Trump at his word.
He said,
"Greenland will be ours."
And
they knew that they were going to have
to fight this Goliath somehow.
And so, you might as well take the place
down with you.
Yeah, no ball balls out, though, you
know? I mean, I seriously didn't think
they had it in them. Yeah. Kudos to
them. Yeah. Yeah, cool. Well, John, um
go and have a great weekend. Um it's
it's the it's the end of the show, but
we'll be back Monday, as we are Monday
through Friday, 9:00 a.m. Eastern Time.
Please We had a If you missed it
yesterday, John and Scott Stanton and I
had a good chat on DMC America. That's
up on YouTube and Rumble. Go check that
out. And uh please stay tuned for TMI
with myself and Millenial Chan coming up
right now. See you Monday, John. See
you.
>> [music]